{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Tale of Two Cities'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the studio album 'X&Y'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Baby Got Back\" by Sir Mix-a-Lot","incorrectAnswers":["\"Bohemian Rhapsody\" by Queen","\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"You're So Vain\" by Carly Simon"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Oh, my, God, Becky / Look at her butt...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Western Australia ","incorrectAnswers":["Victoria","Queensland","Tasmania"],"question":"Which Is The Largest State In Australia","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Mozambique","Brazil","Rwanda"],"question":"Cantonese is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Antonym","incorrectAnswers":["Synonym","Acronym","Hyponym"],"question":"What is the antonym of the word \"synonym\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pierre-Auguste Renoir","incorrectAnswers":["‎‎Edvard Munch","Pablo Picasso","Jackson Pollock"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Bal du Moulin de la Galette\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Matt Monro","incorrectAnswers":["Shirley Bassey","Lulu","Madonna"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film From Russia With Love?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Colombia","incorrectAnswers":["Libya","Eritrea","El Salvador"],"question":"Bogotá is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Silverado","incorrectAnswers":["Cobra","Civic","Giulietta"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Chevrolet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Declaration Of Independence","incorrectAnswers":["The Constitution","The Emancipation Procalation","The Liberty Decree"],"question":"Which 1776 American Affirmation Asserted The Basic Rights Of All?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["India","France","Mexico"],"question":"In which country did the philosophy of Taoism originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Key West","incorrectAnswers":["Miami Beach","Tallahassee","Jacksonville"],"question":"Which southernmost city in the continental US is accessible by a highway completed in 1938 that allowed drivers to reach it from Miami?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Motor Racing","incorrectAnswers":["Track and field","Rowing","Baseball"],"question":"With which sport is Aryton Senna associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","France","Spain"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1958 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Wings","incorrectAnswers":["The Band","The Kinks","Deep Purple"],"question":"Which band did Paul McCartney form after The Beatles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Redford","incorrectAnswers":["Gerard Butler","Michael Fassbender","Jim Carrey"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Avengers: Endgame and Pete's Dragon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Montenegro","Serbia","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Greece?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets","incorrectAnswers":["The Sea of Monsters","The Battle of the Labyrinth","The Lightning Thief"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Not for the first time, an argument had broken out over breakfast at number four, Privet drive'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1914","incorrectAnswers":["1938","1923","1919"],"question":"In What Year Did World War I Begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Work It\" by Missy Elliott","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"A Thousand Miles\" by Vanessa Carlton"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"DJ please, pick up your phone I'm on the request line!\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Swahili","incorrectAnswers":["Punjabi","Hausa","Cantonese"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in Kenya?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"especially as related to Christianity","incorrectAnswers":["human beings killing other human beings","the study and design of machines at the molecular level","the physiological bases of psychological processes"],"question":"What is Soteriology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A dog","incorrectAnswers":["A clown's sidekick","An imaginary friend","A baby toy"],"question":"In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who or what is Santa's Little Helper?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iran","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","Chile","Israel"],"question":"In which country would you find the Lut Desert?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Billy Ray Cyrus","incorrectAnswers":["Bryan Adams","Vanilla Ice","Whitney Houston"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1992 with the song 'Achy Breaky Heart'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Albania","incorrectAnswers":["Latvia","Denmark","Sweden"],"question":"In which country is the city of Tirana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Constantine","incorrectAnswers":["Byzantine","Marcus Aurelius","Trajan"],"question":"Which Roman Emperor moved the capital from Rome to the city now known as Istanbul? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Santo Domingo","incorrectAnswers":["San Juan","Valparaíso","Cartagena"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Dominican Republic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Disturbia'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"F-Series","incorrectAnswers":["Accord","911","Passat"],"question":"Which of these models of car is made by Ford?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thar she blows!","incorrectAnswers":["Land Ahoy!","Dive! Dive! Dive!","Look alive, boys!"],"question":"What is the traditional cry heard when a whaling boat spots a whale?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Aspirin","incorrectAnswers":["Ibuprofen","Paracetamol","Morphine"],"question":"Which drug can be given to prevent blood clots?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The nature of value","incorrectAnswers":["Existence","Very low temperatures","Neural diseases"],"question":"What is Axiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Catherine Parr","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine of Aragon","Jane Seymour","Anne Boleyn"],"question":"Who Was Henry VIII's Last Wife?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Federal Security Service","incorrectAnswers":["Ministry of Internal Affairs","Ministry of Defense","Secretariat for Internal Security"],"question":"What is the name of Russia's main domestic security agency?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rorschach","incorrectAnswers":["The Joker","Venom","Lex Luthor"],"question":"Which antihero, whose mask looked like swirling ink, did Jackie Earle Haley portray in 'Watchmen'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Native Son","incorrectAnswers":["The English Patient","The Metamorphosis","The Moviegoer"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Bigger Thomas'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boston Celtics","incorrectAnswers":["Boston Braves","Boston Capitals","Boston Browns"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Boston?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mountains","incorrectAnswers":["Cats","Soil","Genetics"],"question":"What is Orology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"L. Ron Hubbard","incorrectAnswers":["J.R.R. Tolkien","Joseph Smith","P. T. Barnum"],"question":"Who was the founder of Scientology?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Trojan War","incorrectAnswers":["The Napoleonic Wars","The Crusades","The Punic Wars"],"question":"Which conflict of legend was ignited by Paris and Helen?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Nikolai Gogol","incorrectAnswers":["Virginia Woolf","Alexander Pushkin","Ayn Rand"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Government Inspector'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Two men searching for work in 1920s Mexico convince an old prospector to help them mine for gold.","incorrectAnswers":["Historical events unfold from the perspective of an Alabama man with an IQ of 75.","A skilled forger and conman is pursued by an FBI agent.","After his son is captured and taken to Sydney, a clownfish sets out on a journey to bring him home."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Treasure of the Sierra Madre?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Curmudgeon","incorrectAnswers":["Bumfuzzle","Borborygmus","Deipnophobia"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a bad-tempered person'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Taiwan","incorrectAnswers":["New Zealand","Kosovo","Timor-Leste"],"question":"Taipei is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ursula","incorrectAnswers":["The Evil Queen","Maleficent","Jafar"],"question":"What is the name of the evil sea witch in The Little Mermaid?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Uralic","Niger–Congo","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Deccan' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","Ecuador","Peru"],"question":"In which country would you find the Los Glaciares National Park?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Defense Condition","incorrectAnswers":["Defensive Control","Defeat the Enemy","Defensive Countermeasure"],"question":"What does the military acronym DEFCON stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bruno Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Ludacris","Katy Perry"],"question":"Which American musician released the song 'Just the Way You Are'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Riyadh","incorrectAnswers":["Chisinau","Amman","Islamabad"],"question":"What is the capital city of Saudi Arabia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dmitri Mendeleev","incorrectAnswers":["Isaac Newton","Rosalind Franklin","Michael Faraday"],"question":"Which scientist founded our modern periodic table?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"When they leave & when they arrive","incorrectAnswers":["When they're sad & when they're happy","When they have a birthday & when they get married","When they're ill & when they're healthy"],"question":"In Polynesia , what are the two times it's most customary to place a lei around a someone's neck?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Listen to me, mister. You're my knight in shining armor. Don't you forget it. You're going to get back on that horse, and I'm going to be right behind you, holding on tight, and away we're gonna , go, go!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"What a dump.\"","\"What’s the most you ever lost on a coin toss?\"","\"Chewie, we’re home.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'On Golden Pond'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Swan","incorrectAnswers":["Ring","River","Mountain"],"question":"What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Cygnus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Where the Wild Things Are","incorrectAnswers":["Goodnight Moon","Chicka Chicka Boom Boom","Green Eggs and Ham"],"question":"Which Maurice Sendak classic won the 1964 Caldecott medal for the best picture book for children?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Aguardente ","incorrectAnswers":["Grappa","Schnapps","Marc"],"question":"What spirit is used in fortifying red wine to create port?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bringing Up Baby","incorrectAnswers":["The Crying Game","To Kill a Mockingbird","The Night of the Hunter"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Susan Vance'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dan Brown","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Donna Leon","Frederik Pohl"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Da Vinci Code'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["George Lazenby","Roger Moore","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Dr. No?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sugar Cane","incorrectAnswers":["Banana Tree","Tobacco","Palm Tree"],"question":"From which plant is Rum made?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Sino-Tibetan","Kra–Dai"],"question":"The language 'Saʽidi Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Genesis","incorrectAnswers":["Orchestral Manoeuvres in the Dark","Soft Machine","The Human League"],"question":"Which band includes 'Phil Collins'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rachel Weisz","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Catherine Keener","Frances McDormand"],"question":"Who won the 2005 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Tessa Quayle in The Constant Gardener?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Estonia","incorrectAnswers":["Jordan","Hungary","Egypt"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Tallinn?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1980","incorrectAnswers":["1975","1985","1990"],"question":"In which year was The Shining first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Slavery","incorrectAnswers":["Alcohol","Death","Hunger"],"question":"What did the abolitionist movement of the 1800s seek to end?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Steam Engine","incorrectAnswers":["Electricity","The Wheel","The Printing Press"],"question":"What 18th century invention was considered to be one of the foundations of the Industrial Revolution?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"12 Pints","incorrectAnswers":["9 Pints","7 Pints","10 Pints"],"question":"The Average Woman Has 9 Pints Of Blood, How Much Has The Average Man","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mice","incorrectAnswers":["Lions","Dogs","Monkeys"],"question":"Fill in the blank: \"The best-laid schemes of _____ and men.\"","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Oasis","incorrectAnswers":["Goldfrapp","Kaiser Chiefs","Jethro Tull"],"question":"Which English rock band formed in Manchester in 1991 released the song 'Wonderwall'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mandarin","incorrectAnswers":["Marathi","Aymara","Chewa"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in China?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Haruki Murakami","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Umberto Eco","Søren Kierkegaard"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Norwegian Wood'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Crete","incorrectAnswers":["Babylon","Mexico","Turkey"],"question":"Where were the ancient script of Linear A and Linear B found?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Drone","incorrectAnswers":["A Billy","A Buck","A Macho"],"question":"What would you call a male ant?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Rice Burroughs","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Tarzan of the Apes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iran","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Albania","Montenegro"],"question":"Tehran is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The A.B.C. Murders'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Thailand"],"question":"Which of these countries borders India?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bulls","incorrectAnswers":["Fellas","Dogs","Blokes"],"question":"What are male cows called?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1982","incorrectAnswers":["1977","1987","1992"],"question":"In which year was The Thing first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Caliban","incorrectAnswers":["Prospero","Miranda","Ariel"],"question":"In Shakespeare's 'The Tempest', which character is described as 'a howling monster', 'a most scurvy monster' and 'some monster of the isle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Shaggs","incorrectAnswers":["The Velvet Underground ","The Vamps","Eagles"],"question":"Which American rock band is renowned for having music described as both ‘the worst of all time, yet a work of unintentional brilliance’?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pale Fire","incorrectAnswers":["Portnoy's Complaint","The Tin Drum","The Swimmer"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Charles Kinbote'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nevada","incorrectAnswers":["Arizona","Colorado","Utah"],"question":"Which US state is known by the nicknames \"The Sagebrush State\" and \"The Silver State\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","France","Mexico"],"question":"With what country is Fidel Castro associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mozart","incorrectAnswers":["Beethoven","Liszt","Wagner"],"question":"Whose Life Story Featured In The Movie 'Amadeus'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Casablanca","incorrectAnswers":["For Whom the Bell Tolls","Heaven Can Wait","The Human Comedy"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1943?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fernet","incorrectAnswers":["Nsafufuo","Akevitt","Canelazo"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Argentina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Physicist who made a significant contribution to understanding electromagnetism","incorrectAnswers":["Greek mathematician","Composer of music during the classical and romantic period.","Leader of US forces during the  American Revolution."],"question":"Which of the following describes James Clerk Maxwell?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nightwish","incorrectAnswers":["Haloo Helsinki!","Hanoi Rocks","Children of Bodom"],"question":"Which Finnish symphonic metal band released the album 'Once'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["Southeast Asia","Central Asia","Europe"],"question":"From which part of the world do blueberries originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Butterflies & Moths","incorrectAnswers":["Leopards","Turtles & Tortoises","Sharks"],"question":"For What Is Lepidoptera The Scientific Name?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Serbia","incorrectAnswers":["Cyprus","Turkmenistan","Israel"],"question":"Belgrade is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A kindle","incorrectAnswers":["A gang","A stud","A fall"],"question":"What is the word for a group of kittens?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"42","incorrectAnswers":["20","3","51"],"question":"According To \"The Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy\" what number is the answer to everything?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Fast Times at Ridgemont High","incorrectAnswers":["Pulp Fiction","The Searchers","The Pink Panther"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Jeff Spicoli'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The North","incorrectAnswers":["The South","The East","The West"],"question":"Which was the victorious side in the U.S. Civil War?","difficulty":"medium"},